Carnegie Seminar on Political and Administrative Development Director's records, 1959-1973 C158
Indiana University Archives
Director's records
1959-1973
1962-1965
Indiana University Archives
Carnegie Seminar on Political and Administrative Development
C158
1 cubic foot
The Faculty Seminar on Political and Administrative Development was established by the Dept. of Government (now Political Science), in 1962. Originally funded by a grant from Carnegie Corporation, it became better known as the Carnegie Seminar. Consists of correspondence, memos, meeting minutes, proposals, and annual reports.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Advance notice is required.
Historical Note
The Faculty Seminar on Political and Administrative Development was established by the Department of Government, now the Department of Political Science, in 1962. Supported by a $105,000 grant from the Carnegie Corporation, it quickly became known simply as the Carnegie Seminar. Professor Fred W. Riggs was the Seminar's first director, assuming the post when the initial grant was awarded in February 1962. William Siffin was also involved as a co-coordinator of the Seminar, and assumed the directorship while Riggs was on leave from September 1962 to June 1963 and following Riggs' departure from Indiana University.
The Carnegie Seminar brought together faculty and advanced graduate students at IU, as well as supporting the visits of faculty from other institutions. Funds from the Seminar's grant provided financial support which allowed faculty members to conduct research related to the Seminar's theme. Broadly stated, the Carnegie Seminar had three goals: to support studies in the field of political and administrative development using the resources and interests of Government Department faculty; to integrate diverse research by encouraging the development of basic theory; and to stimulate the flow of information between participants and scholars from other disciplines and institutions. Although funds from the Carnegie grant were exhausted in 1967, the "Carnegie Seminar" name continued to be used by the department for a number of years.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Correspondence and Subject.
Scope and Content Note
The Records of the Carnegie Seminar are divided into two series. The Correspondence series is arranged alphabetically and contains both incoming and outgoing correspondence. The outgoing correspondence is primarily that of the Seminar director. Materials in this series date from 1959 to 1973.
The Subject series is also arranged alphabetically. It includes the Seminar's annual reports from 1962 to 1965. Files relating to the Seminar's meetings and the political and administrative development program are also contained in this series. Span dates for this series from 1962 to 1967, with the bulk of the material falling between 1962 and 1965.
Related Material
For more information on William Siffin see also the following IU Archives collections: William J. Siffin papers, Collection 157; International Development Institute records, Collection 159; Pasitam Director's records, Collection 160.
Acquisition Information
Received 18 January 1996 from Louise Siffin of International Programs, Accession 96/001.
Carnegie Seminar on Political and Administrative Development -- Archives; Carnegie Seminar on Political and Administrative Development -- Records and correspondence; Siffin, William J. -- Correspondence; Siffin, William J. -- Correspondence -- Selections
- Correspondence, 1959-1973
  - "A" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Ashton, John, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - "B" Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Banks, Art, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1964-1972 (Box 1)
  - Committee on the Center for the Study of Development, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Coulborn, Rushton, 1962 (Box 1)
  - "D" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Distribution List for Published Materials, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Dotson, Arch, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Eisenstadt, S.N., 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - "F" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - "G" Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - "H" Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Harik, I.F. (Box 1)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Hobbes, Milton, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Holt, Robert, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Horrigon, Fred, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - "I" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Isaak, Alan C., 1964 (Box 1)
  - "J" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - "K" Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Laves, Walter H.C., 1964 (Box 1)
  - Libenow, J. Gus, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - "M" Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Memos (Box 1)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Milne, R.S., 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - 1962-1968 (Box 1)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 1)
    - 1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
  - Mosher, Frederick, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Obermeyer, Jerry, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Participants, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Plans, 1959-1964 (Box 1)
  - Prospective Members, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Publications, 1967 (Box 1)
  - "R" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Randall, Ray, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Report to the Carnegie Corporation, 1965-1973 (Box 1)
  - Research Proposals (Box 1)
  - Riggs, Fred W., 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - "S" Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Sathyamurthy, T.V., 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Siffin, William, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Simpson, Dick, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Somjee, A. H., 1961-1964 (Box 1)
  - "T" Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Tanter, Raymond, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Textor, Robert B., 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Untereiner, Wayne, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - "V" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Vatikiotis, P. J., 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Visitors, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - "W" Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Wood, W.A.R., 1964 (Box 1)
  - "Y" Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
- Subject Files, 1962-1967
  - Annual Report (Box 1)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Classification Project, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Meetings (Box 1)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1)
      General
      (2 files)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, Executive Committee, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Political and Administrative Development Program (Box 1)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
      (3 files)
    - Proposal (Box 1)
      - 1966 (Box 1)
      - 1967 (Box 1)
  - Programs, 1963 (Box 1)